#### Michael Lewis

513-254-1822 | michaellewis1689@outlook.com | Xenia, OH 45385 https://www.linkedin.com/in/michael-lewis-74b6143/

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am an expert web developer with over 15 years of experience building high quality and performant websites following mobile-first, component-based design and agile development methodologies. I have experience with Full Stack web development, CRM setup and migration, Data Engineering and eCommerce. I have a certification from Acquia for Drupal development, and my work on City of Hope has won an award. I've worked with teams of various sizes in various roles, all the way up to team lead. I am fully set up to work remotely but am willing to relocate if necessary. I'm looking for an opportunities to lead web development teams, use emerging technologies like AI, and spec into data engineering

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Technology Specialist, VML (via TekSystems)

November, 2021 - Present

- Lead the team tha build <a href="https://www.cityofhope.org">https://www.cityofhope.org</a>, winning the 2022 <a href="https://www.cityofhope.org">eHealthcare</a>
  Alliance Platinum award for Best Site Design for a Hospital with 200-399 Beds.
- Lead the development team that launched a redesign of Lutron's luxury website with new components, a Content Hub, and an Image gallery to showcase projects and designers that utilize their products. (<a href="https://luxury.lutron.com">https://luxury.lutron.com</a>)
- Developed an ETL pipeline DAG using Google Cloud Composer to facilitate the migration of CRM data from Salesforce to Braze for Wendy's.
- Rebuilt the MyFembree website for Pfizer with a fresh mobile-first design and improved sitemap to help patients find information about how MyFembree can treat their symptoms and talk to their doctor about whether it is right for them.
- Developed updates to <a href="https://www.vml.com">https://www.vml.com</a>
- Developed updates to <a href="https://www.wendys.com">https://www.wendys.com</a>

## Senior Drupal Developer, NLRB (via Puyenpa)

May, 2020 - Nov 2021

- Senior Drupal Developer and Technical Architect for <a href="https://www.nlrb.gov">https://www.nlrb.gov</a>
- Took over the project lead of a redesign and migration project that was 6 months behind schedule and saw the completion of the project on-time by the original deadline.
   Objectives included completing a migration from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8, completing a re-theme, completing implementation of single sign-on, and other features
- Solved DevOps problems that were plaguing the development process
- Maintained compliance of the website with the high security standards that all federal computer systems must adhere to.
- Solved website performance problems.
- Developed a series of Spanish language translated pages
- Developed website features to enable improved user experience for those seeking to download records from the large volume of case history that was made available through the site.

## Senior Drupal Developer, Duo Consulting

# January 2017 - April 2020

- Built the new website for Freeborn & Peters LLP that involved a migration from Drupal 7 to Drupal 8 (<a href="https://www.freeborn.com">https://www.freeborn.com</a>)
- Built an online point of sale for Chicago Botanic Garden <a href="https://www.chicagobotanic.org">https://www.chicagobotanic.org</a>
- Developed updates to Dremel Digilab <a href="https://digilab.dremel.com">https://digilab.dremel.com</a>
- Developed updates to MuchLaw https://www.muchlaw.com
- Developed updates to Bracewell <a href="https://www.bracewell.com">https://www.bracewell.com</a>
- Developed updates to Figo Pet Insurance <a href="https://www.figopetinsurance.com">https://www.figopetinsurance.com</a>
- Developed updates for Domu Chicago
- Developed updates for Lipkin Higgins - <a href="https://web.archive.org/web/20170816225750/https://www.lipkinhiggins.com/">https://www.lipkinhiggins.com/</a> (later, https://www.peterhigginslaw.com/

### Senior Drupal Developer, TQINet/The Beracha Foundation July 2008 – December, 2016

- Developed an online e-commerce system for WCSG Radio in Cornerstone, Michigan to drive their bi-annual pledge drives.
- Built a Drupal Commerce based non-profit fundraising system for non-profits to host pledge drives and fund raising efforts. (Used as backbone for WCSG Radio).
- Built numerous websites for various non-profit organizations and missionaries to facilitate engaging their donors to support their work. Organizations supported include EBM, InFaith, Santa Claus Inc, WCSG/Cornerstone, David's House, Serra International, Anderson Church of God, Clan MacNlcol, Swim MAC Carolina
- Built ECommerce donation pages for EBM, InFaith David's House, and more
- Built websites for GE and Center State Bank
- Built a REST API intermediary for MaestroSoft to communicate with Etapestry CRM
- API and ETL integrations of data into the Etapestry CRM

#### **EDUCATION**

# Bachelor of Arts, Management Information Systems

May, 2006

Cedarville, University

## **SKILLS**

Drupal, Linux, Apache, MySQL, PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SASS, Node.js, React, Python, Google Cloud Platform, Acquia, Pantheon, Docker, DNS, SSL, CDN, Github Actions, Microsoft Azure, Atlassian (JIRA/Bitbucket), Figma, Bootstrap, Twig, Tailwind

#### AWARDS/RECOGNITIONS/VOLUNTEER WORK - (OPTIONAL)

- 2022 <u>eHealthcare Alliance Platinum award for Best Site Design for a Hospital with</u>
   200-399 Beds.
- Acquia Certified Drupal Developer.

April, 2018

- Sunday School Teacher
- Soccer Coach
- Amateur Musician